CONTACT

me@benparisot.com 503-719-3537 www.benparisot.com







EDUCATION

Pacific Northwest College of Art

Web Design Certification Program, pursuing

Alchemy Code Lab

800+ hours advanced full stack JavaScript training

Willamette University

B.A. English and Communications

STACK

Tech

HTML5/CSS3/Sass
JavaScript
Node.js
Express
React/Redux
Jest/Enzyme
MongoDB/Firebase
Travis/Jenkins
Docker

Tools

Git/Github Heroku Postman/Compass Jira/Confluence Sketch/Illustrator Photoshop/After Effects

BEN PARISOT

DESIGN-DRIVEN FULL STACK ENGINEER

I'm a full stack software engineer with a passion for intuitive design, test-driven development, and writing DRY code. I believe good design drives clear product requirements and leads to better technical understanding. I'm a creative at heart and view every new project as an opportunity to build something elegant and useful.

PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

Experience shipping full stack code

including API back ends with clean RESTful endpoints and component-based front ends with performant state management.

Over 10 years in the tech industry

with experience in all parts of the software development lifecycle and deep understanding of agile management practices. 10 yrs using HTML/CSS, 4 yrs using vanilla JavaScript and jQuery, 2+ yrs using JS libraries and modern web frameworks.

User-centered approach to design

with experience leading and/or designing UX and component architecture for such clients as Cascade AIDS Project, Oregon MESA, Cartoon Network, Kaiser Permanente, and State Farm.

RECENT SIDE PROJECTS

- **Weather.** ∣ React, D3, StyledComponents, Firebase
- A serverless web app that takes a user-entered US zip code and draws an interactive 12-hour temperature forecast line graph using the D3 visualization library.
- Mega-Nap | Node.js, Express, React/Redux, MongoDB
 - A full-stack web app that allows front end developers to input data and generate RESTful API endpoints for use in their own applications.
- Robot Haikubot | Node.js, Express, MongoDB

 A Twitter bot that sends a randomly-generated haiku to those that ask for one!

CONTACT

me@benparisot.com 503-719-3537 www.benparisot.com







COMMUNITY

Portland Varsity Gay League

Member

Queer-focused sports league, member of soccer and dodgeball teams

PDX JR Dev Meet-Up

Leadership Team
Managing the volunteer
website development
team, organizing and
running events

Friends Accountability Brigade

Founding Member
Grassroots political
organizing, letter writing
campaigns, fundraising,
get-out-the-vote efforts



BEN PARISOT, CONTINUED

WORK EXPERIENCE

Alchemy Code Lab | Full Stack Engineer

Sept 2019 - Present

Jan 2019 - Sept 2019, Apprentice Engineer
As lead full stack engineer in Alchemy's App Lab
department, I design and build new front end components,
write calls to our backend API, and write back end routes
and database queries to serve the appropriate data at scale.
I also perform code reviews with other developers, approve
and merge PRs, and resolve issues and bugs from the QA
backlog.

Helios Interactive | Tech Producer July 2016 - Jan 2019

As Tech Producer at Helios I worked with clients, producers, designers, and developers to keep projects on schedule and deliver working apps under strict deadlines. My role included architecting apps with developers, running sprints with project team members, identifying and prioritizing bugs with QA, and handling onsite and app store deployment with our ops team.

Roger That Agency | Digital Director Nov 2014 - June 2016

As Digital Director at Roger That I was responsible for sourcing and managing developers for clients' web projects, launching websites after development was complete, and maintaining site themes post-launch. After deployment I would make presentational changes to the look and behavior of site components as well as help clients with email set-up, domain transfers, and other technical issues

Foster Digital Marketing | Owner/Founder Sept 2010 - Sept 2014

As a freelance digital marketer and web producer I was responsible for managing contractors and working with clients through all stages of a web development project. I also performed SEO site audits on existing websites to help commercial sites perform better in search results, implemented and managed social media and PPC campaigns, and wrote blog posts, articles, and website copy.